NWAFOR CHINONSO

Front End Software Developer

Innovated, highly motivated and design-inclined Front-End Developer with 2 years of experience working with JavaScript, HTML/CSS to deliver exceptional customer experiences. Adept at contributing to a highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions, and determining customer satisfaction.

Lagos, Nigeria. +2348146334317

nonsonwafor70@gmail.com

LinkedIn Portfolio

EXPERIENCE

AREABOX, Remote

Frontend Developer

Oct 2021 - Nov 2023

- Performed user experience quality assurance testing to identify and remedy shortcomings.
- Increased website traffic by 20% through SEO optimization.
- Produced websites compatible with multiple browsers.
- Implemented responsive design principles to ensure that web applications were accessible on all devices.
- Migrated a multi-page user experience into a single page app, improving customer engagement by 10%.

SIDE HUSTLE, Remote

React Developer Intern

Jan 2021 - Aug 2021

- Learned React and Redux and applied to daily tasks to improve efficiency and productivity.
- Assisted in frontend development tasks, including website layout, UI enhancement and bug fixes.
- Collaborated with the development team to improve website performance and optimize code.
- Built cross-browser compatible and accessible complaints websites, resulting in 30% faster load time than industry average.
- Was part of a team of 4 front-end developers, to debug the team's code to provide additional perspective and catch previously missed errors.

SKILLS

HTML CSS

JAVASCRIPT

REST APIs

TAILWIND CSS

REDUX

REACT

FIREBASE

WORDPRESS

 ${\sf JEST}$

GIT AND GITHUB

TYPESCRIPT

TDD(TEST DRIVEN DEVELOPMENT)

EDUCATION

University of Lagos

B.Sc. Chemical Engineering 2016 - 2021

OTHER

- Dev XP member
- Just Breathe Asthma Foundation (JBAF) volunteer